Inventory of the Herman Recht Papers 1943-1946
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Folders 601-700: 5 September 1945 to 24 December 1945
  - (7)
    - Folders 691-700: 25 November 1945-24 December 1945 (7, 10)
      Hears that Dr. Smit will stay on until March 1 and be promoted to Lt. Commander because they need him; talks about how men there are eager for only one thing, being discharged and sent home; hears that administrative heads might want to keep men there longer, to ease the transition. An accident occurs with one of the buses taking recruits from camp to the football game in Williamsburg; reads an article in PM with comments by William Carlos Williams about Ezra Pound. Has to tell men that they are being moved from the department, but leaves that for Lt. Kennedy to worry about. Will come home from 28 December to 8 January. Talks about his pending discharge, which is now definite in the near future, process beginning January 1. Has a steak sandwich with pineapple, the best meat he has had while at the Camp. Hears that the German PoWs are putting on a Sudermann play, Heimat. Reads an article about the disorganization of the Allied occupation of Germany.
  Series 8: Folders 701-779: 25 December 1945-19 January 1946
- Folders 701-779: 25 December 1945-19 January 1946
  - (8)
      Subseries 1: Folders 701-710: 25 December 1945-19 January 1946
    - Folders 701-710: 25 December 1945-19 January 1946 (8, 1)
      Plans what he wants to do with all his Navy clothes after he is discharged. Goes on leave for 10 days back up to Pittsburgh. Is eager, even though his military service was not hard, to return to civilian life. For the first time, when Recht returns to Camp, it is the Camp that now feels far away, instead of his home. Notices that the camp store is slowly reducing its stock, in anticipation of the Camp closing; hears that the man who will be replacing him, Boulieu, has not been up to the task. The child-parent exhibit, for which Recht helped to get information, closed. Talks about a sardine carton lost from Esther’s father’s store. Hears a theory that colds never leave the body, just lay in wait. Thinks about painting their house, and discusses colors; is trying to buy as much as possible before leaving the Camp. Hears about a steel strike, and discusses its impact; talks about the physical one gets when leaving the service. Hears about Brille taking a vacation to Mexico on one of his leaves.
      Subseries 2: Folders 711-720: 20 January 1946-26 January 1946
    - Folders 711-720: 20 January 1946-26 January 1946 (8, 2)
      Asks about why one of his friends would not take her job back at the Social Work school. Talks about how he believes slim people are healthier than “persons heavier.” Talks about friends thinking about going to law school, and about how only 180 nylons were sent to the Camp, so he could not buy any. The Camp gets another influx of recruits; talks about someone who is “quite a misfit”; sends some towels to friends back home. Sees “Scarlett Street”; thinks that once he is moved to Induction, for preparation to go home, that he will not come to the office much, but let his replacement find his way. Starts cleaning out his drawers in his office. Needs to think out his positions on “the problem of white-Negro interrelationships.” Arranges with Lt. Sorenson about coming into the office while in Induction, for part of the time; wants to take a vacation after out of the service, but not sure if to take one to New York City or just to rest at their home.
      Subseries 3: Folder 721-729: 26 January 1946-2 February 1946
    - Folder 721-729: 26 January 1946-2 February 1946 (8, 3)
      Finally gets information about where he is moving, and when. Gets an interview to assign him to a specific separation center. Sends a lot of things he wants at home through the mail to Esther, instead of packing them. Finally gets the date and time that he will be leaving. Starts trying to say goodbye to people from the camp. Starts filling out all sorts of forms. Sends his last letter from the Camp.
      Subseries 4: Folder 730-779: Fragments
    - Folder 730-779: Fragments (8, 4)
      Writes a letter detailing his morning routine at the Camp, probably from early in his stay there. Talks about people in a stay at the Williamsburg Lodge. Hears Lew talk about how Dorislee is immature; visits the Personnel Office and has fun pointing out two mistakes they made. Camp has been receiving letters from men who have been transferred. Talks about his feelings on his assignment to and at Peary and the way other men think of their assignments. Talks about a Romanian, now a US citizen, working at Peary. Talks about how the situation is in the office after Frankie has left, and how much work he does. Talks to Phillips about libraries and their purpose. Talks about plays at the Nixon Theater, which is in Pittsburgh. Thinks that if the war were to go on for another year or so, he might try to work for the UNRRA[United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration]. Sees nothing but grave potential danger in the after-war period. Talks about “books on and by Negroes.” Talks about marks that Lt. Kennedy gave out to the men. Thinks he might be able to get a GE electric iron. Writes what someone, possibly Lt. Kennedy, wrote for his recommendation for commission. Talks about race riots in Philadelphia. Sees families at the pool; sees the movie “See My Lawyer;” hears that trains are being cancelled for troop movements. Hears about men being moved and reassigned. Hears a bit from men still in shock about Roosevelt’s death. Talks about how the boot recruits and the chiefs are so eager to learn and get out of Peary, and Recht just calmly does his job. Talks about how nice it was to hear Esther and Sid on the phone; discusses transportation to Williamsburg, and its difficulties. Talks about sending food back to home. Hears about more men leaving for Cleveland and elsewhere. Does not see any of the men from his original barracks anymore; hears that most lawyers who come in believe they should be in administration or the legal department. Hears about a sailor who was in the hospital for 74 days but is still in the service. Talks about what he misses about Pittsburgh. Talks about the wife of another family, whose husband is also in the military, moving in with Esther; hears about the possible closing of the Camp. Hears some of the opinions the seamen have for yeomen. Writes a letter on Recht’s Furniture letterhead. Hears that the Captain of the Camp believes that the war is being fought to save Christianity. Two letters from the summer of 1940, written to an Eleanor, and not written by Herman Recht; letters have holes cut out of them, indicating censorship.